Guide to the Jacqueline de Jong Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1957–1979; Series IV
  - Gruppe SPUR, 1961–1967
    The subseries largely contains printed material, such as tracts, posters, and periodicals, issued by the German avant-garde group, in addition to files on the trials of Gruppe SPUR members by the German authorities and the invention of the sham character Bolus Krim by artist Erwin Eisch and the collaborative RADAMA.
    - Brochure "Unver Bindliche, Richt Linien", [1962] (Box 22, Folder 466)
      By Christofer Baldeney, Rodolphe Gasché and Dieter Kunzelmann
    - Exhibition catalogue "Lothar Fisher - Heimred Prem", Galerie van de Loo, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 467)
    - File "Bolus Krim SPUR - Radama", 1961 (Box 22, Folder 468)
      Contains a memorial bookmark, newspaper clippings, and two typed texts with manuscript corrections: Susanne Carwin's text "Slechtes gewissen" and de Jong's "Bolus eventualis"
      - Restricted fragile newspaper clippings, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 518)
    - File "Procès SPUR", 1962–1964 (Box 22, Folder 469)
    - Periodical Anschlag vol. 1, no. 1-2, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 470)
    - Periodical Ludus, no. 2, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 471)
    - Periodical Texturen, no. 9, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 472)
      Inscribed on the inside cover by Dieter Kunzelmann.
    - Poster for exhibition SPUR: Bilder und Plastiken at Galerie van de Loo, 1962 (Box 30 (Broadside))
    - Tracts and manifestos, 1961–1964 (Box 22, Folder 473)
      Including the tract "Nicht Hinauslehnen!" by de Jong, Jorgen Nash, and Ansgar Elde.
  - Protests of May 1968, 1965–1970
    The subseries contains photographs, tracts, and newspaper coverage of the protest movement, as well as of student and labor unrest in the years leading to the May 1968 protests.
    - Clippings related to student protests, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 474)
    - Photographs by Helle Nielsen, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 475)
      Six original photographs of the May 1968 events with the photographer's stamp on the verso.
    - Photographs by Eddy Posthuma de Boer, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 476)
      Sixteen original photographs of the May 1968 events with the photographer's stamp on the verso, published in Cees Nooteboom's book De Parijse beroerte. Accompanied by a letter from Boer to Hans de Jong.
    - Political tracts, 1967–1968 (Box 23, Folder 477)
      Contains Division Leclerc, "La machine infernale"; C.P.A.O., "Combat pour l'autonomie ouvrière"; and anynonymous, "Le coup de Strassbourg des 'autonomes': la révolution trahie par la police".
    - Publications
      - Action, no. 18, 19, 20, 27, and 29, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 507)
      - Algemeen handelsblad, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 508)
        Page from 1965 January 12 issue.
      - La cause du peuple, no. 19, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 509)
      - L'Enragé, no. 1, 2, 5, 6, 7, and 11, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 478)
      - Le Figaro littéraire, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 510)
        Pages from 1966 August 4 and December 1 issues with articles on student protests and Situationism in Amsterdam and Strasbourg.
      - God nederland & oranje, no. 10, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 511)
      - Kontrast, no. 2, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 479)
      - Le Monde, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 512)
        Complete issue of 1968 July 20, and pages from October 2.
      - Le Nouvel Observateur, no. 183, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 505)
        1968-05-01
      - Paris Mai-Juin 1968: 94 documents (Paris: Editions S.E.R.G.) (Box 23, Folder 480)
        Edited by Edouard Dejay, Philippe Johnsson, and Claude Moliterni.
      - Le Pavé, tract no. 1, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 513)
      - Vrijlage van blij nederland, unnumbered, undated (Box 23, Folder 481)
- Professional and Personal Papers, 1962–1975; Series V; .21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by document type.
  Series V. Professional and Personal Papers, contains a small number of documents relating to de Jong's professional art career and her personal finances.
  - Biographical statement and curriculum vitae, circa 1966 (Box 24, Folder 482)
  - Clippings from Dutch and Italian newspapers, 1968–1975 (Box 24, Folder 483-484)
  - Invitation cards for exhibitions featuring Jacqueline de Jong, 1968–1973 (Box 24, Folder 485)
  - Invitation list, undated (Box 24, Folder 486)
  - Invoices for exhibitions, 1963–1970 (Box 24, Folder 487)
  - Personal financial records, 1963–1970 (Box 24, Folder 488-489)